Daniel Shaw

Web Developer / IT Specialist

San Antonio, TX 78244 shaw.j.daniel@gmail.com +1 469 505 7215

Award-winning IT specialist / Wev developer with 10+ years of experience in device support, break/fix, and networking. Attended Coding boot camp (prior to its dissolution) for Front End Development, and continue to create user-friendly and responsive website for clients on a contractual basis.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Freelance Web Developer

self-employed - Remote September 2020 to Present

Freelance web developers create eye-catching and user-friendly websites to generate web traffic and promote their clients' products and services. Unlike staff web developers, freelance web developers are independent contractors who may work for an individual or business on a short- or long-term basis.

Front End Developer

Lambda School - Indianapolis, IN February 2021 to August 2021

Attended Lambda School, cohort was cancelled due to Covid. School advised there would not be any future classes due to internal issues. School was later rebranded but was not able to return under new ISA rules.

Apple Master

Best Buy - Scottsdale, AZ November 2019 to August 2020

Apple Computing Master is responsible for creating a world-class shopping experience for our customers while meeting their technology needs with Apple products and services. Masters build quality relationships with retail consumers to provide them with relevant and memorable Apple product demonstrations.

Systems Administrator

BUTI Yoga - Scottsdale, AZ May 2017 to November 2017

Contractual responsibilities included day to day technical support issues, backup and replication, server maintenance and coding email templates sent from design.

Help Desk Technician

SouthWestern Eye - Scottsdale, AZ January 2017 to May 2017

Provided help desk support to end users for proprietary software. Answered questions about product features and to resolve problems, as well as installing software for developers, project managers, and quality assurance team members.

Backup Administrator

Xlcon - Phoenix, AZ March 2015 to January 2017

Responsible for monitoring usage levels of storage and proactively managing the capacity of systems and services. Also assisted in Tier 2 Escalations from RMM ticketing system.

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science

University of North Texas - Denton, TX 2009 to 2013

Skills

- Mac OS X
- IOS
- Networking
- Network Security
- Servers
- Information Technology
- Hipaa (5 years)
- Problem-solving
- Flexibility
- Team Work
- Reliability
- Web development (3 years)
- React (1 year)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Unit testing (3 years)
- CSS
- HTML5
- Linux
- MySQL (1 year)
- Node.js (1 year)
- Git
- GitHub (5 years)
- Front-end development
- Bootstrap

- APIs
- REST
- Agile
- User Interface (UI)
- · Remote access software
- TCP
- TCP/IP
- · Computer hardware
- Windows
- Operating Systems
- MongoDB
- Software deployment (10+ years)

Links

https://github.com/danimalcrackrz

Awards

Team Impact

April 2016

The award recognizes and rewards those that make significant contributions to the work and mission of the organization.

Assessments

Basic Computer Skills: PC — Expert

August 2019

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Expert

Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Verbal Communication — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Highly Proficient

Problem Solving — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Analyzing relevant information when solving problems.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Attention to Detail — Proficient

August 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting

information.

Full results: Proficient

Technical Support — Expert

September 2019

Applying protocols to identify errors and solutions in order to maintain system function.

Full results: Expert

Software developer fit — Proficient

February 2022

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Proficient

Basic computer skills — Expert

August 2019

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Expert

Technical support — Proficient

February 2022

Performing software, hardware, and network operations

Full results: Proficient

Technical support: Customer situations — Proficient

February 2022

Responding to technical support situations with sensitivity

Full results: Proficient

Basic computer skills — Expert

February 2022

Performing basic computer operations and troubleshooting common problems

Full results: Expert

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Groups

The Trevor Project

January 2007 to Present

I volunteer my time regularly, with a strong commitment of at least a few hours, or a couple times a month (this varies across programs). Communicating openly and regularly with the parent/guardians or with the school liaisons to emphasize friendship and the importance of a stable foundation. Mentoring through consistency and dependability to maintain a positive presence in the Mentee's life. Most importantly listening to and respecting the thoughts and viewpoints of the mentee's and focus on their strengths.